<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4001/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4001/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-07T17:39:55+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Leadspod.</title><subtitle>No more issues with delivery. Our AI engine interacts positively with your emails, increasing your sender reputation and preventing spam.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How to Prepare an Email Account for Cold Email Sending</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-How-to-Prepare-an-Email-Account-for-Cold-Email-Sending.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Prepare an Email Account for Cold Email Sending" /><published>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-How-to-Prepare-an-Email-Account-for-Cold-Email-Sending</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-How-to-Prepare-an-Email-Account-for-Cold-Email-Sending.html">&lt;p&gt;Deliverability is critical when sending cold emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estimates are that over 20% of emails never reach the inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We frequently see new email accounts used for cold email campaigns terminated mid-campaign. With Google’s spam change in January 2019, it’s getting harder to get into the inbox. You must first warm up your new email account to avoid this before sending out a cold email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article will explain how to warm up an email account before sending cold emails to avoid the SPAM folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The warmup procedure involves sending emails from a new email account, starting small and increasing daily. When a user opens a new email account, the provider limits daily email sending. New accounts will be unable to use it fully. For example, Google Workspace subscribers get 2000 emails per day. But you are restricted until you have established a good reputation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optimal deliverability should take 8-12 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preparation time depends on email volume and participation during the warming process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cold email must first reach the recipient’s inbox. Positive engagement will help you build a relationship. Before sending a cold email, warming up the account helps avoid the spam filter, get into the inbox, and get opened more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preparing an Email Account for a Cold Email!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customize Emails Sending emails to friends and colleagues to start conversations is the first step. Send ten to twenty emails from your new email account to begin. Assuring constant engagement with the initial emails will help increase email volume. Over time, growing confidence in your authenticity prepares your email account for email campaigns. When using the manual method, personalize the subject line to improve response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this manual process, send emails to Gmail, Yahoo, Outlook, iCloud, Godaddy, Zoho, Aol, Exchange, and Yandex. Sending to all major email providers will help you get past spam filters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintain email Threads in your warmup emails to increase deliverability. So start by sending emails from your old accounts and responding from your new ones. Regular interactions are critical here, as this is an 8-12 week process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join Newsletters from publications in your industry. Subscribe to a minimum of 10-15 newsletters. Return to your mailbox to confirm each newsletter subscription. It will verify your account and expand your email inbox. Receiving emails is as important as sending emails to warm up a new email account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep a time difference between two emails Each email service provider has its algorithm for confirming delivery. So show those algorithms you’re not a robot by not sending too many emails at once. Sending many emails in a short period can harm your domain’s reputation. To avoid this, keep a significant time difference between two emails while warming up your new account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sending too many emails in a single session triggers spam filters, and email providers will block account temporarily or permanently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Begin small and simple. Begin with a small list of 20-30 reliable receivers, augmented by friends and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personalize email to persuade your recipients to open and respond.  Create a unique subject line to maximize open rates.  Personalization is key to provoking responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid spam words like FREE, GRAB, and 50% in your emails. These will trigger SPAM filters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep the information simple and plain, with few links and media files (photos, movies, GIFs) for best delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always include an unsubscribe link. One spam report against a newly created account can damage your reputation. Having an unsubscribe link in your emails gives your recipients a choice not to receive further emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system exists to filter spam. Following best practices shows algorithms that you are not a spammer. And perhaps most importantly, remember that improving your reputation as a sender is easier than improving a spammer’s reputation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write as a genuine human being would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, don’t forget to verify your accounts with these three critical components technically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SPF creates a record in your DNS (Domain Name System) that identifies all servers allowed to send emails on behalf of a domain. Because SPF Authentication is on the sender’s side, the recipient Email Service Provider gives the sender’s domain a clean bill of health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DKIM prevents email spoofing with a digital signature and ensures that your message reaches the intended recipient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DMARC records use SPF and DKIM records to reassure the recipient’s email service provider (ESP) that the email is not the result of a misleading activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leadspod now provides a service that takes care of all this for you. Sounds interesting. Please check out our warmup service.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Deliverability is critical when sending cold emails.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Transforming strangers into customers.</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-Write-cold-email-that-transforms-strangers-into-customers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transforming strangers into customers." /><published>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-Write-cold-email-that-transforms-strangers-into-customers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-Write-cold-email-that-transforms-strangers-into-customers.html">&lt;p&gt;Write a cold email that creates curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it’s frustrating to send out your first campaign and get no response. Most people fail because they believe they are good at cold emailing, which they are not. Second, they believe their product or service is so great that everyone should automatically book a meeting with them. As a result, I’d like to show you a simple but highly effective way of writing cold emails that will increase response rates and turn strangers into customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I’ll show you an example of a wrong email, followed by an example of a good email. I have changed the person’s name and company to protect the person’s identity. But this is an actual email that someone sent, and we’ll break it down and show you why it doesn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so let’s get started, so this person said hi, Rob. Crazy times. I heard online learning is blowing up. What do you say? Is it time to beef up R&amp;amp;D? First, I’m not sure what he means by “strengthening your R&amp;amp;D.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m John from x agency, nice to meet you. Do you want to benefit from our online learning expertise and decent developers? Send us a message to discuss potential collaborations. Regards, John.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking it down, I have no idea what this person does or how he helps me. Often, people write emails to offer something to someone, but I have no idea what he has to offer. It’s too vague to respond. Second, the grammar is incorrect. People won’t take you seriously if you don’t check your grammar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my best cold email templates is The Pain Formula, and it’s super simple to use because it’s broken down into four parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first one has a relevant intro, introducing yourself and what you do or why you should be connected. Second, we’ll discuss the customer’s pain. What aches does this person have? And, how do you get rid of those pains? Finally, the call to action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should they do next? Make sure every element is crystal clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me show you an example of an email I wrote to get ideas and use the elements in your emails. Let’s pretend I’m in marketing or content management, and I’m writing an email to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m trying to sell to Jack Frontend, correct? How would I email myself? So let’s get started. That first part is relevant, so I’ll say, “Hey Jack, I just watched your latest YouTube video, and I thought it was great.” My videos on YouTube are very relevant. If he gets it, he’s on the same page as me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, we’ll talk about pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep probing the person’s pain. So I can say something like, after watching the video, I checked out your website and noticed you didn’t have a blog yet, which I don’t. Surprisingly, you haven’t started converting your YouTube videos into blog posts to increase organic traffic to your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been making videos, but I also have a website but no blog, and it would be simple to turn my YouTube videos into articles or blog posts that people can pay for and read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This email is relevant because I am thinking about it, and if they have something to help me, I am more willing to meet with them. But it’s all about context, knowing your customer and their pains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third part focuses on the solution. How will you solve these issues?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in this email, I’ll say that if you’re interested, my company helps YouTube content creators like yourself start highly ranked blogs using their existing YouTube content. Plus, we handle all tech and content management, making it easy for you. Clients A, B, and C are examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here I am, starting with the pain. You won’t get this extra traffic by blogging your YouTube videos. So I offer a solution. If you want something, I can quickly get it for you. Just say yes, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to make it as simple as possible for the other person to understand what I’m saying and agree to meet with me, and I included some clients I worked with, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in this situation, you want to name-drop past clients relevant to the current prospects. It would be too long to tell them what you did for them. You want to say, “I worked with these people.” It’s very relevant to what you’re doing, and I’m like, oh, he worked with these people I admire? So, I want to meet him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the solution, most people fail to include a clear call to action, which means once someone reads your email, what is the next step you want them to take? If you’re interested in learning how to help you get more traffic with blogging, what does your calendar look like? Just schedule a time on my calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming that they are accessible on that day and time, you request a meeting via email and then sign off, best, John, or whatever your name is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve got it all together, this is the Pain Formula structure I showed you at the start. We understand the person’s pain and make it hurt so that when we present our solution, it is more appealing. Following the solution, you have a clear call to action. Don’t say, “Hey, drop a line,” because that’s illogical. So, drop a line? You need to be precise. Let me know your calendar or set up a time to talk. So don’t copy my exact words. You should tailor the intro, pain, solution, and call to action to your style. If you do these simple things and follow this template, your response rates may skyrocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can send thousands of these emails and get tons of meetings from them. I’m confident that you can do it, too, if you follow this framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, here is my cold email Pain Formula template for you to use.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Write a cold email that creates curiosity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A step by step how we use cold emails</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-a-step-by-step-how-we-use-cold-emails-to-get-clients-and-grow-our-business.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A step by step how we use cold emails" /><published>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-a-step-by-step-how-we-use-cold-emails-to-get-clients-and-grow-our-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-a-step-by-step-how-we-use-cold-emails-to-get-clients-and-grow-our-business.html">&lt;p&gt;Use cold emails to get clients and grow our business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/illistrations/abstrakt-design-139.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re an entrepreneur looking to grow your business, skills, and income, make sure to read this article to the end. You’ll learn how we use cold emails to get clients and grow our business free and with no risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to know the exact industry the decision-maker that we are reaching out to how big these companies will give us a precise picture and allow us to create a message that converts. So the first step is to create an ideal client profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step two is to create a list of prospects who fit that profile, so let’s say we’re targeting design companies with 10 to 50 employees in Seattle or Washington. We need to know whom we’re targeting to create a list of prospects who fit those criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three is to create a cold email messaging sequence designed to generate appointments right now. The goal of these emails is to make an appointment and not a sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll go over steps 1 through 3, and then step 4 is to call those who said yes to learning more about your service and close the deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So first off, create an ICP to know whom you’re going to be targeting. Step two is to create a list of people who fit your ICP who match the criteria, and step three is to create a messaging sequence. Step four will be a separate article about the sales process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need for step one, making an ICP, is a Google sheet with the columns below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Industry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company size&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Job title&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pain points&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expected results&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Benefits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you should know the industries you’re targeting. Well, we’re targeting computer software and information technology, and these are from LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started with the USA to keep it simple because it was a large enough pool to target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The larger the company, the more complex and more extended the sales cycle is, so you want to target people from small businesses in that 11 to 50 employee range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started with founders and then moved on to CEOs and CMOS for job titles. These are all people who can benefit or want to talk about our service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And most important for your messaging, what are the pain points and problems of these companies?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, what are we offering to the market to help them solve these pain points and problems?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what are the expected results, and what are the benefits?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step two is to build your prospect list. There are many ways to do this, but I’ll show you where we find our leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When targeting B2B, we’ll use LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s say we want to target only dentists who offer root canal treatment, which is a specific procedure. We’ll hire someone on Upwork to create a targeted list of those prospects who fit those criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these are the main places we use. You can use Google to save money or use some lead providers from the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seamless&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Findthatlead&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sales.rocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll do reviews of the different providers in separate articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you’ll have a CSV with their email, first name, last name, position, company, website, industry, company size, location, and LinkedIn profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll use an email verification provider from the list below to ensure the email won’t bounce and your deliverability won’t suffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unbounce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zeroin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll do reviews of the different providers in separate articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many outsource this process to a virtual assistant. They will also import the list into your tool to run this process with minimal maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step three, I’ve created a messaging sequence designed to generate appointments. But you can’t just copy and paste this and then complain about not getting appointments, sales, or clients. You must experiment and test things on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created an excel sheet with the following columns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subject&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The big promise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proof&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Call to action&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Authority and credibility content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The email has a subject line, an introduction, significant promise, and proof. You can use third-party proof if you don’t have proof like market research or white label provider case studies. Then a call to action and a PS if you have a trust-building guide or white paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to always split test everything especially subject lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the intro, you want to make sure it’s just casual and something you’d send to a friend or a new colleague, right? Jack’s LinkedIn intro I found your profile on LinkedIn and thought I’d reach out given your background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big promise or no-brainer we have is a service for B2B SAAS companies that can help you generate eight to twelve more demos every month without wasting your sales rep’s time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proof we’ve helped similar companies like B and C automate their lead generation and book eight to twelve more sales appointments per month, which have helped increase sales. Does this sound interesting to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to get them to say yes or no to the call to action. If it is a no, remove the prospect from our list. We set up a time to chat if it is a yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We send out a LinkedIn guide in the PS, so as you can see in my ICP sheet, we play on the pain points and the expected results of our service. You want to make sure that these are in your email. They are critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people won’t respond to the first email, so that we will follow up three to four days later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they don’t respond within a week, we send them one more email, and if they still don’t respond within a week, we send them one last email. My intent is not to be a pain, so that’s my final follow-up. You could touch them a few more times on different platforms like LinkedIn or Facebook, depending on where your ICP is active.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Use cold emails to get clients and grow our business.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cold email deliverability analysis (no tech)</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-cold-email-deliverability-analysis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cold email deliverability analysis (no tech)" /><published>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-cold-email-deliverability-analysis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-cold-email-deliverability-analysis.html">&lt;p&gt;Why do cold emails fail?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/illistrations/abstrakt-design-350.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready for some cold email deliverability analysis? To avoid being spammed with your cold emails, you must overcome three obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you don’t want recipients to mark your email as spam; otherwise, you’re going to have a hard time getting people to see your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also don’t want to be blacklisted by email providers. If Google blacklists your domain for spamming, you’re finished. You don’t want that, and neither do spam filters. If you use traditional spam words like free, you’ll get marked manually, automatically, or by spam filters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do you avoid them all? Let’s examine them closely. The first is to prevent spam reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you stop a cold email from being marked as spam? The first step is to customize the email’s first line to appear, not as a spam email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see your email on your phone and want to mark it as spam, then it’s spam, and you need to rework it. You’ll be blacklisted if you send it to your recipients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must also target the right prospects. Make sure your list is clean. People who don’t own a fashion store will mark your email as spam if you talk about fashion because it’s irrelevant. So make sure you’re checking your lead quality. If you send to the wrong people, you are spamming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People shouldn’t know that you sent an email to a thousand people if you do it right. It should look like you sat at a computer and sent the email just to them. You can only achieve this with a clean and hyper-targeted list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, look human and ask for a response. Getting replies to your emails is the easiest way to avoid spam or the Promotions tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make it simple, ask for a response by saying something like, “Would you mind if I sent over a few times for a quick call?” So if we can write our emails in a way that looks human, we’ll get responses and avoid being marked as spam because they’re responding to us. The manual flag thing is the easiest to get through by mastering cold email by copywriting and sending things people want to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the more technical ones. You don’t want to be flagged by email or service providers. This is when Google looks into how you send emails and decides whether you’re spamming or not, destroying your domain if you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how to avoid it? If you are starting your domain, don’t go out and send a thousand emails a day. You must prepare. The previous article recommended tools that allowed you to ramp up consistently without getting hit immediately by your internet service provider or email client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, use automation with care, whether it’s checking your lead lists or customizing your first lines. Sending unproven emails to many people will get you marked as spam. Send 40 emails, check the open and response rates, and send another 40 to keep improving. Don’t send 5000 unproven emails, or you’ll be marked spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can still be the greatest email writer ever by sending it to 40 people. You don’t need to send it to 5000. You will eventually reach three, four, or five thousand people, but you can significantly improve your results by starting slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid being marked by your ISP, the third thing you can do is reduce bounces by using an email verifier. You want to make sure your emails are going to real people. I try to keep our bounce rate in the single digits as low as possible. Google, Gmail, or your service provider will see if your bounce rate is too high and mark you as spam because you’re guessing email addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re using an email verification tool and are getting a catch-all email or have 70% confidence that the email will go through, don’t send it to that email. Only send it to those with higher confidence because you don’t want that bounce rate to be high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you buy a list of 5000 and send to 20 first, and five of them bounce, you just saved yourself from having a blacklisted domain because if you send to the entire list, email providers mark you as spam, which is why I always recommend sending in small batches first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test and improve, you should use different templates. If you send the same message every day without changing anything, your ISP will mark you as spam. You should always use a custom first line to avoid this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, monitor your reputation. There are tools to check if providers have marked you as spam. Some of those tools also let you warm up your email, which I’ll cover shortly, or set up a new domain without breaking the rules. You need to be able to identify spam quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll also notice it if your open rates plummet dramatically, as in sending emails with a 60-80% open rate. You send emails to the same list the following week and get a 3% open rate. If you’re getting marked as spam, go to our public Facebook group, or I can help you one-on-one in the private community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, these spam filters put you in the spam folder. To send emails through custom domains, you must first set up your email infrastructure correctly. If you’re using Google Workspaces, Google’s email sending tool, you’ll need to move your servers over to your email sending tool, so you’re not sending from your email sending tool’s server but Google’s server or the server from the email provider that you choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a warm-up email account means sending emails to people who will respond, making Google think your account is real. You’re not just here to spam people. You’re getting replies and replying and getting newsletters. Some tools will automate this for you, some I recommended in previous articles, so check that out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid spam trigger words, and be aware that the algorithms will mark you even if your content isn’t spammy. All of this boils down to not spamming if you have a list of 5000 or 800000 contacts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Why do cold emails fail?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cold Email OR Marketing Email</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-cold-email-or-marketing-email.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cold Email OR Marketing Email" /><published>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-cold-email-or-marketing-email</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-cold-email-or-marketing-email.html">&lt;p&gt;How to tell marketing emails from cold emails?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/illistrations/abstrakt-design214.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can I send mass outreach emails? Stay tuned as I show you my system and discuss different scenarios to send bulk cold emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read on to learn how to work and send out cold emails in under ten minutes. Email marketing sends emails to specific people to increase sales, web traffic, or audience engagement. There are several types of email marketing. To start, you can send out newsletters and promote your services to your subscribers. The second type is cold email marketing, and the third is bulk email marketing, or spamming. In short, cold emails are not spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we explain the differences, you should know whatever you send or do. Someone may consider you a spammer. One of my subscribers reported me as spam. He’s my fan. He joined my email list and told me that I was spamming after he opted in. The difference between a cold email or a legal cold email and a spammy cold email is your goal, the goal of your campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t know the goal of your campaign if you send thousands of emails in bulk. Your goal is to get affiliate or CPA links clicked. And this is 100% spamming during cold mailing. It’s a hard call where someone says, Hey, we have this offer. Do you want to meet? Do you want to know more about my services? So is requesting a meeting, calling, or offering assistance to specific people. For example, in cold emailing, we usually send hundreds or thousands of emails per day to particular people like CEOs of companies or people working in specific fields offering our services. So you can arrange a meeting with them. It all depends on your goal, volume, and interest in your email from the recipient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that sending cold emails to our company to request meetings is not spamming. So it’s clear. Let’s not waste any more time. From here on out, we know that cold email marketing is sending mass emails to specific people to offer services, set appointments, or build a business. That said, you want to track your open rates and possibly your click rates when using email marketing. You need to manage your email lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you need an email marketing service. MailChimp, GetResponse, and a Webber active campaign are popular email marketing companies. These big email marketing companies don’t allow cold emails because it attracts spammers. So, to send cold emails, you need a specific system. The first is to use Gsuite, which I detailed on my channel. So you can use G Suite and GMs to build an email marketing system. The other option is Office 365.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you get it. Your email system is now ready to send outreach emails tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">How to tell marketing emails from cold emails?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to find the right people to cold email</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-how-to-find-the-right-people-to-cold-email.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to find the right people to cold email" /><published>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-how-to-find-the-right-people-to-cold-email</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-how-to-find-the-right-people-to-cold-email.html">&lt;p&gt;If they don’t respond within two weeks, move down one level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I imagine myself as the recipient of a cold email. We’ve all received cold emails, and the bad ones are easy to spot. Why it’s wrong — a few things stand out. In your Gmail inbox, you’ll see the subject line and a portion of the first line, which will help you decide whether to delete or open the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, make sure the subject line is neutral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I prefer generic subject lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love ‘Hi from Jack.’ I love ‘Quick question.’ Questions like “Question about Tide” or “Question about General Electric” work well for us. Those generic subject lines work because they don’t turn people off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you pitch your product in the subject line, you’re more likely to be deleted than to be read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the first line of the email must be specific to their business. I like to compliment people, so I might say, “Hey Mark, ‘Congratulations on working with Power Rangers!’ ‘Hey, I looked at your website and loved the food photography.’ Some specifics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’ve already beaten most of the nasty cold emails because you’re not in spam, and you’re are opened. But we’re talking about responses, and the best way to get someone to respond to an email is to assume they already know it’s true. Then tell them the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find your website and like your work with Power Rangers, you can say something like that. ‘My name is Jack, and I work for marketing firm…’ Or if I’m talking to a consulting agency and say I do marketing for consulting agencies, they’ll instantly light up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just got off the phone with the CMO of a major telecom company, and they had these two main issues. We have solutions. My question is, do you have similar problems?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CEOs of agencies with revenues between $1 million and $20 million will likely have similar issues, whereas the CMO’s of the same companies may have different problems. We learn about these two issues from our customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My recent coaching call with someone who sells Facebook ads in the e-commerce space revealed that videos sometimes sell worse than static images, so he recommended testing both. And that is a specific idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Let me know if this interests you.’ We’d love to talk more with you over the phone. ‘Can I send over a few times?’ The call-to-action is irrelevant as long as it is a question they can answer. Surprisingly many emails end in a period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re the CEO of a large company, say T-Mobile, would you buy Facebook ads or delegate that decision to a CMO? Would the CMO delegate to the Director of Marketing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So thinking about the target company’s decision-making tree helps me find titles, and then I use LinkedIn to find the target customer. Typing in Director of Marketing, T-Mobile, for example, brings up a list of people, and then it goes back to those assumptions to see who will buy from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re selling something that benefits the field sales team, then you’re selling something that helps the field sales team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t want to do all of the research, the quickest way is to start with the CEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they don’t respond within two weeks, move down one level. Email Marketing Director. If they don’t respond in two weeks, move up. I do not recommend sending multiple emails to the same company simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My number one sales tip is to treat every client call like a doctor diagnosing a disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when I sell marketing services to agencies, I talk to the agency owner. From our previous conversations with other agency owners in the same position, I have a good idea of how they think and what problems they may be facing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I won’t say it out loud. Stating what we do, I then ask about their existing marketing. Do you currently hire a marketing vendor to manage your marketing? Do you have KPIs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask questions that don’t have a clear answer but help me understand their needs. The easiest way to sell anything is to listen to a question. Your sales managers may have given you scripts or key points to hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider a case study that relates to it, and then answer the question based on your experience. When someone says, “Oh, we’ve always done all our marketing internally, and it’s just me,” I could say, “That happens in many agencies.” The founder tries to do everything, including marketing, sales, and production. I know many marketing agencies that seem to be crushing it with their clients, but when I look at their websites, their inbound leads are way down, and that’s what we help with.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I listened to his response, internalized it, and then brought it up in our pitch as one of our case studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congrats. You’ve got a boost. Use it now. Remember to subscribe to level up. See you tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">If they don’t respond within two weeks, move down one level.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Make your offer a no-brainer</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-make-your-offer-a-no-brainer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Make your offer a no-brainer" /><published>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-make-your-offer-a-no-brainer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-make-your-offer-a-no-brainer.html">&lt;p&gt;How to make your offer so strong that it becomes irresistible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make your offer a no-brainer, you need to do the following four things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First, emotionally sell them on what we offer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manage buyer’s remorse and refunds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remaining objections.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The fourth one is secretly genius, you will see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with increasing the value of your offer to the point where it’s a no-brainer for your clients. Understanding your target market is the first step in selling them emotionally. Write compelling copy that speaks to them and meets them exactly where they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assume, for example. You’re promoting a diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number one mistake I see is people going out and saying, “This is what other personal trainers charge.” I only charge this, and I’m better than them. Nothing matters because I don’t want what you have yet, and they don’t believe you can solve their problems because they are unique. And they don’t think you can help them. What do we do? Simple, we must address the mental conversation of your prospect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you’re selling a weight loss program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a girl in her mid-20s who can’t lose weight. She wants to lose 20 lbs. She’s been trying for a year and still can’t do it. We’ll talk about her pain points and how I remember you looking great in high school. But now they’ve tried on your 20-year-old jeans. They no longer fit. You go to the beach with your friends, but you’re not comfortable in your bikini. So you avoid going to the beach. You avoid eating dessert because you’ll be called a pig. You’re trying to lose weight while eating dessert, and no matter what you do, you can’t seem to lose that belly fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’ll be listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The science says what matters is what your prospect feels, so she feels like she’s tried everything. And she can’t lose weight to change her life, so that’s the one we’ll address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first rule of sales is to make your prospects feel understood. They’ll automatically assume you know the answer. Before talking about the features and benefits, you need to get this right. Knowing your target audience and demonstrating that you understand them is critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you offer email marketing as a service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re calling your prospect. Your client says previous freelancers blew it. Most freelancers would immediately jump in and say, “Oh well, I’m not like them; I’m way better, and here’s why, and I charge less, and I’m reliable, and…” Features and benefits are irrelevant here. You haven’t sold them yet. Take a deep breath and go into their world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say I get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most freelancers are unreliable. They constantly lie and give you shoddy work and have difficulty communicating. You must always follow up, and it is never up to par. And, to be honest, no matter how many times you tell them, they never get your brand voice right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client is thinking, Oh my god, someone finally understands me because you demonstrated understanding of their reality in 5-10 seconds. They’ll say, “Oh, he gets it because of what you just said.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think they’ll decide? You have extensive industry knowledge and experience. Two, you’re not like other freelancers who are late, don’t capture the brand voice, are unreliable. You made them understand this without you having to hard-sell yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we’ve sold them emotionally, they feel understood. You seem to understand and have a solution. The prospect is now hyper-alert. Now you can discuss your work and the benefit of working with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the fat loss example, you jump in and say, okay, usually my hourly rate is $1,000. But, you know, I’m determined to get 50 people in the best shape of their lives for this new case study program. I’ll give those 50 people personalized meal plans, workouts, supplement recommendations, and daily accountability text check-ins for just $200 instead of the usual $100 an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, they would not have been interested in hearing about your offer, but now that you’ve soled them emotionally, they’re much more receptive, and they’re like, that sounds like a no-brainer sign me up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we’re not done yet because people still believe they are unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has their own set of reasons why they are different, unique, or why they’ve tried this before and failed, or why you are no different from the other coaches out there, and you must handle this. Social proof testimonials and results from previous clients, preferably clients in a worse situation than the client you’re talking to, are a great way to overcome such objections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, this prospect claims to have the worst genetics ever. My fat genes make me unable to lose weight no matter how hard I try. I hate diets and exercise that don’t work for me. What can you do now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll talk about Ann, your client, who you’ve been working with for six months. The worst genetics you’ve ever seen, she began a hundred pounds overweight. She had a history of diabetes and obesity, and previous diets had failed her. And none of her previous personal trainers worked, but I started working with Ann six months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We created a custom diet, nutrition, and exercise plan. Ann has been losing five pounds every month, and she is now in the best shape of her life and loving it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to handle those kinds of objections is through proof of other people who have done it, starting from worse situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people want to join my program, I get many objections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I work full-time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have another business.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m not sure I’ll have time to do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To overcome objections, show examples of others who have done it, starting from worse situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a bonus pro tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth super ninja way to make the value of your offer a no-brainer and eliminate any objections from your prospects is to remove friction from your offer. How can you reduce friction to a minimum? The most significant stumbling block is upfront payment. They have to pay you three grand, two grand, 1500 dollars, or whatever it is upfront, and they’re hesitant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prospect’s objection is that they are unsure if you can deliver value and if they’re going to make a return on their investment. This offer is ideal for starters who don’t have many clients yet. Once you get a few clients, I can tell you that everything becomes much more manageable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you can offer them a great value proposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m that confident in my services and results. I’ll write you two weeks’ worth of free emails, and if they don’t work, don’t pay me. If they work better than your current emails, my usual rate is $200 an hour. And we can discuss what it might look like if we worked together sounds fair? It’s a no-brainer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work for commission instead of a retainer; they owe you nothing if you don’t deliver. But if you crush it for them, they’ll gladly pay you ten grand in commission if you make them a hundred grand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about how you can make your offer as frictionless as possible, and I guarantee you will start signing more clients than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s how to make your offer so compelling that it’s a no-brainer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">How to make your offer so strong that it becomes irresistible?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">10 Tips To Improve Your Cold Emails</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-tips-to-improve-your-cold-email.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 Tips To Improve Your Cold Emails" /><published>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-tips-to-improve-your-cold-email</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/article/news/10-tips-to-improve-your-cold-email.html">&lt;p&gt;This article was just updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1-make-your-emails-more-inclusive&quot;&gt;1 Make Your Emails More Inclusive&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than one cold outreach email has failed because a marketer misidentified a prospect: Getting some aspect of your prospects wrong, no matter how fantastic your offer is, almost guarantees that they will erase your email. Spending time drafting more inclusive emails is a quick approach to get rid of a huge roadblock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2-findthe-most-effective-time&quot;&gt;2 Find the Most Effective Time&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider timing based on what you know about the person or what you’ve learned from your investigation. If you got the notion to contact this individual because they were just featured in a magazine, they’re undoubtedly getting a lot of pitches at the moment. Consider when that person’s inbox is less crowded, and when they are more likely to read and respond to your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3-identify-the-decisive-individual&quot;&gt;3 Identify the Decisive Individual&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow time to locate the appropriate point of contact. You don’t want to waste time investigating only to discover that you contacted the incorrect person and received no response. Utilize sites such as Linkedin to ascertain a person’s position inside an organization, and compose the email with an eye toward their issues and how you may assist them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;4-avoid-taking-up-too-much-space-in-someones-inbox&quot;&gt;4 Avoid Taking Up Too Much Space in Someone’s Inbox&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re communicating over email, keep it brief and direct. Make your request explicit and demonstrate how the person you’re contacting will benefit from replying. Because people’s inboxes are already clogged, it’s critical to demonstrate your worth. Additionally, attempt to customize your email. Individuals can recognize whether they are being spammed with a generic message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;5-run-numerous-subject-line-experiments&quot;&gt;5 Run Numerous Subject Line Experiments&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can have the best email in the world, but it will be ineffective if few people open it! We always experiment with different subject lines in order to increase our open rates, and the effort is well worth it. You’ll get the best results by customizing the subject lines based on an article or email they authored, a significant change they made to their website, or a recent mention in the press. Concentrate on those areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;6-launch-a-warm-up-email-campaign-for-cold-calls&quot;&gt;6 Launch a Warm-Up Email Campaign for Cold Calls&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send an email campaign to warm up your cold call outreach technique. Export the email campaign’s leads and target your cold call outreach precisely to those leads. Then export the leads who opened the email campaign and target this section for secondary outreach. Email campaigns and reporting data are excellent methods for marketers to connect the links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;7-research-three-levels-deep&quot;&gt;7 Research Three Levels Deep&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cold outreach is based on the exchange of value. Consider the following framework while creating a cold pitch. The first level is defining your “ask.” The second level is defining the value you’ll provide if they express interest. Level three is all about defining the value you’ve previously supplied them with prior to delivering the first email. If you incorporate components from all three tiers into your introductory email, you will experience phenomenal success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;8-concentrate-on-the-location-industry-and-scale&quot;&gt;8 Concentrate on the location, industry, and scale&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cold outreach is segmented by geography, industry, and company size. Contacting a local business always yields better outcomes. Industry type aids in the development of an engaging subject and material for an industry-specific project. The size of the business helps us determine the type of people we need to contact. Additionally, the combination of these criteria results in a reduced sample size that is easier to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;9-utilize-transcripts-of-sales-calls&quot;&gt;9 Utilize Transcripts of Sales Calls&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conduct analysis and evaluation of past cold calls to see what worked and how replies were perceived. Chorus.ai is an excellent tool for accomplishing this and for determining which words perform best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;10-approach-it-from-their-point-of-view&quot;&gt;10 Approach It From Their Point Of View&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than cold-contacting people for their business, think out how to give value to their life first. Bear in mind that individuals are primarily concerned with one thing: “What’s in it for me?” Ascertain that your outreach to prospective clients clearly communicates the level of value and assistance you wish to deliver. While this may seem obvious, surprisingly few cold outreach strategies adhere to this fundamental concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-3-bonus-tips&quot;&gt;And 3 bonus tips!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;11-use-a-straightforward-closing-with-a-specific-reasonable-request&quot;&gt;11 Use a Straightforward Closing With a Specific, Reasonable Request&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bear in mind that the receiver receives a high volume of cold emails throughout the day, and many of them miss the mark when it comes to concluding the message. The seller either requests too much, too fast, or is ambiguous about what they want from the recipient. A straightforward conclusion that includes a specific and fair request, as well as flexible scheduling choices, goes a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;12-use-multiple-platforms&quot;&gt;12 Use multiple platforms&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of outreach techniques are platform-specific, such as email, phone calls, or direct mail. Utilize a service like FullContact to locate contacts across social media platforms, allowing you to establish a presence in many areas rather than relying just on phone calls or emails. Spread it out over time to avoid prospects feeling bombarded and “stalked.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;13-constantly-follow-up&quot;&gt;13 Constantly Follow Up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personalizing your cold outreach email is no more a nice-to-have; it is absolutely necessary if you want to be noticed. However, many people overlook their initial try. Create an email series that will be automatically sent to your target individual every few days. This way, you’ll remain top-of-mind for them and boost your chances of being recognized.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">This article was just updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Five parts for a great email.</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/article/news/5-parts-to-a-great-email.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Five parts for a great email." /><published>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/article/news/5-parts-to-a-great-email</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/article/news/5-parts-to-a-great-email.html">&lt;p&gt;Email is the foundation of our daily communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/illistrations/abstrakt-design-350.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day, an average office worker receives 121 emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our emails are generally mediocre. They’re either too long, annoying or contain a typo. Or, as a boss, you should not send a devastating goodbye email to laid-off employees. But, for traceability, having many people read it, for time zones, emails are vital, and other forms of communication cannot replace it. But did you ever learn to write an email? Like you, I send and receive a lot of texts and emails. I use them to keep in touch with friends, partners, and colleagues worldwide; I only get to see them a few times a year in person, but I need to maintain a solid human relationship, so how can we do this successfully?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick is to focus on small details that add up. It turns out that by tweaking five small things, you can make your email more effective, save time, and even have fun writing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we go, the five parts for a great email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, imagine being invited to Buckingham Palace for dinner by the Queen. You dress up, sit down at the most magnificent dining table you’ve ever seen, and then you get the banquet menu, and it’s written in french. It’s all about first impressions. Your first impression is what sets a royal dinner apart from a McDonald’s Big Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three things could make a great subject line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Call for action: Meeting tomorrow, please respond!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Short as possible: Hey! :-)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connection to the receiver: Missed you, how’s Friday?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to know which of these three emails people would open first, so I added two more boring subject lines, a bank statement, and a generic welcome message, and asked over 300 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The call to action won, followed by the short one, and finally the one indicating a connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, state your request in the subject line. The second email is dull and in black and white. Different punctuation and emojis can add color and, more importantly, feel to that email. I call digital body language, and we need it to be ourselves. Imagine someone wanted to send me a thank-you note via email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    Dear Jack, thank you for coming over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full stop ends that sentence. Did you know that a teen who ends a text message with a full stop is annoyed? Let’s try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    Jack, thanks for visiting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much better because of the exclamation mark. However, we become too lazy to include some form of hello in our email. Please say hello—one last time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    Hey guy, awesome that you dropped by :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, it’s a bit informal for a business setting, but that smiley makes all the difference. To go all-in or resonate with Gen Z, include a gift. That same teenager who was annoyed at you is now thrilled. What about emojis and gifs in business emails? To compare digital body language to spices in your email recipe, you may want to add more or less hot curry or hot sauce to your pot depending on the culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short emails are almost always answered. Why? Researchers from NYU MIT and Boston University discovered that most business emails are skimmed and sometimes deleted. In fact, every word you type after the first 40 reduces your chances of getting an answer. This is the tweet principle. If your email is longer than a tweet or 140 characters, consider calling instead. It’s true that some of you may be thinking that your meeting notes can’t be that short, but the parts where you want something to happen or need someone to do something can and should be separated from the rest and put as an attachment instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That magical word that would instantly grab the attention of any single person in the world is your name. According to Dale Carnegie, a person’s name is the most important sound in any language. He wrote about communication almost a century ago. Why not apply it to emails? We all have a narcissist who uses names in critical situations. For example, if a request in an email is critical, start over with the recipient’s name. Research also shows that mentioning a familiar name increases response rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what makes an email that always gets an answer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Say what you want in the subject line&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use digital body language depending on the setting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be as brief as a tweet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use names and key moments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no perfect email, and they are correct. You want something from someone, who is still a human being, so the magical ingredients can help. It’s not about the ingredients; it’s about the dose. So, the next time you write an email, imagine the recipient and try to bake it to their liking using all these ingredients. Oh, and this is number five. Do you recall Steve Jobs presenting the coolest product? He’d say one more thing at the end of his keynote, and out would come to the new iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a cue from Steve Jobs, but the one thing you want the reader to know is the one thing you’re most nervous about saying, under the ps line. The last impression is less famous than the first impression, but it is just as powerful because it sticks in the reader’s mind long after the rest has faded. Here’s an example. I can’t send an email asking where my money is if someone forgets to pay me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I can do, though, is write an email that says, hey, you’re a great audience. Thank you for having me p.s. That last invoice wasn’t paid yet, smiley, which always gets the job done.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Email is the foundation of our daily communication.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cold emails aren’t just for sales or business</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/article/news/cold-emails-are-not-just-for-sales-or-business.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cold emails aren’t just for sales or business" /><published>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T17:39:18+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/article/news/cold-emails-are-not-just-for-sales-or-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/article/news/cold-emails-are-not-just-for-sales-or-business.html">&lt;p&gt;The story of Maddie Bregman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cold emails aren’t just for sales or business. You can use them for getting advice, building relationships, or finding a job, so if you don’t want to be an entrepreneur, you can use cold emails to reach out to people in the field you’re interested in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maddie Bregman started a company, and her first client, was the NFL, and she got them to sign through cold emailing the Vice President. She used to go through executive CEO CMO’S and CEO’S but learned that these people are receiving hundreds of cold emails a day. Instead, she emailed a vice president, had an initial conversation with someone on their team, and closed them as clients a few weeks later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She also used cold email to get responses from Mark Cuban, Sheryl Sandberg, and Arianna Huffington.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She says people are more likely to respond if we can add value upfront when sending cold emails. Don’t ask busy people to grab a coffee so you can pick their brain, and then ask if you’ll commit to being your lifelong mentor. Those cold emails get ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She tries to live by this idea of the third door. It’s the idea that life, business, and success are like a nightclub. There are three ways in the first door is the main entrance where the line curves around the block and where 99% of people wait hoping to get in the second door is the VIP entrance where billionaires and celebrities slip through the third door is the entrance where you have to jump out a line running down the alley and sneak through the kitchen there’s always a way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prepare for a TedX talk, she asked people who have given great talks, so she emailed Mark Cuban, Ben Horowitz, and Beth Comstock and asked them a straightforward question how do you give a really good talk and they all got back to her. Mark Cuban, one of the sharks on Shark Tank, said to relax and tell her personal story. Ben Horowitz is one of the founders of Andreessen Horowitz, a venture capital firm that has invested in companies like Facebook and Pinterest. He said the three keys to an excellent presentation are a compelling opening, a strong ending, and keeping the two as close together as possible Beth Comstock, the vice-chair of General Electric, said to get out of my head and be present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get out of our comfort zone when we use the third door, and when we’re not afraid to try, we grow even if we don’t know where to start.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">The story of Maddie Bregman.</summary></entry></feed>